<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>/blog/</id>
  <title>English Blog - Blog</title>
  <subtitle><![CDATA[Blog of abstracts of scientific articles for CPE Lyon.]]></subtitle>
  <link href="/blog/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="/blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <updated>2020-03-04T17:33:40+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>English Blog</name>
    <uri>/</uri>
  </author>
  <entry xml:lang="en">
    <id>/blog/how-to-optimize-online-learning-in-the-age-of-coronavirus/</id>
    <title>How to optimize online learning in the age of coronavirus</title>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>The article deal with the solutions to optimize online learning with a five key. The article is from <strong>phys.org</strong> and was written by <strong>Andrew Martin</strong>.</p>
<p>Due to the spread of the new coronavirus, online learning for school students is increasing. In order to remedy this, the educational psychologist who wrote this article, propose five key considerations for educators : Instruction, Content, Motivation, Relationships, Mental Health.</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Instruction</strong></li>
</ol>
<p>Regarding the principles of Load Reduction Instruction, online lessons must be very clear and well-structured, delivered in little chunks. When the the students have the basics, they can then provide more independent and self-directed online learning activities.</p>
<ol start="2">
<li><strong>Content</strong></li>
</ol>
<p>Moreover, the material is very important. The teacher have to be sure to use the best material in order to provide the most comfortable lesson to the students. Also, it is important that the content is not too difficult too soon in order to not confusing the student early in the learning process.</p>
<ol start="3">
<li><strong>Motivation</strong></li>
</ol>
<p>There is one area of motivation particularly relevant to online learning: self-regulation which is represented in the Wheel by self- and task-management, planning, and persistence.</p>
<ol start="4">
<li><strong>Relationships</strong></li>
</ol>
<p>Concerning this point, in an online environment, it is recommended that teachers maintain contact with the class in different ways, for instance : via email, the school's online learning platform, video, blogs, and class chat-groups.</p>
<ol start="5">
<li><strong>Mental Health</strong></li>
</ol>
<p>If mental health hurts, learning usually suffers. As a result, it is important that all students are clearly informed of who to contact inside or outside the school if they are in difficulties.</p>
<p><a href="https://phys.org/news/2020-03-optimize-online-age-coronavirus.html">https://phys.org/news/2020-03-optimize-online-age-coronavirus.html</a></p>]]>
    </content>
    <link href="/blog/how-to-optimize-online-learning-in-the-age-of-coronavirus/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <published>2020-03-04T17:33:40+01:00</published>
    <updated>2020-03-04T17:33:40+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:lang="en">
    <id>/blog/mathematicians-develop-new-theory-to-explain-real-world-randomness/</id>
    <title>Fast Share, Android's answer to Apple's AirDrop</title>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>The article deal with the possibility of sharing files between Android products easily. The article is from <strong>phys.org</strong> and was written by <strong>Peter Grad</strong>. </p>
<p>In brief, Google is preparing to launch a brand new app for file sharing between Android products in the update Android 11.</p>
<p>In fact, the application is not yet officially announced but some media analysts spotted a reference to a new Fast Share feature that will allow users to exchange files wirelessly if they are in close proximity. This reference was found in a bug report.</p>
<p>Regardless of the name, the feature will be a competitor of Apple's popular AirDrop, which lets users effortlessly transfer files between iOS and MacOS devices.</p>
<p><a href="https://techxplore.com/news/2020-03-fast-android-apple-airdrop-due.html">https://techxplore.com/news/2020-03-fast-android-apple-airdrop-due.html</a></p>]]>
    </content>
    <link href="/blog/mathematicians-develop-new-theory-to-explain-real-world-randomness/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <published>2020-02-26T16:36:53+01:00</published>
    <updated>2020-02-26T16:36:53+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:lang="en">
    <id>/blog/test/</id>
    <title>Seductive details inhibit learning</title>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>The article deal with the positive use of seductive details for learning. The article is from <strong>phys.org</strong> and was written by <strong>Sara Zaske</strong>.</p>
<p>All goes with a funny thing such as a cat video or even background music. Indeed, it can keep students from understanding the main content.</p>
<p>These so-called &quot;seductive details,&quot; information that is interesting but irrelevant, can be detrimental to learning by the look to a meta-analysis by Washington State University researchers published in the journal Educational Psychology Review recently.</p>
<p>This result was obtained by cross-referencing 58 studies and is as follows: People who learned with seductive details performed lower on learning outcome measures than those who learned without them.</p>
<p>Finally, that doesn't mean the course doesn't have to be cool, but just make a little more effort to think about how we can make the learning activity itself much more appealing and interesting, according to Sundar.,</p>
<p><a href="https://phys.org/news/2020-03-seductive-inhibit.html">https://phys.org/news/2020-03-seductive-inhibit.html</a></p>]]>
    </content>
    <link href="/blog/test/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <published>2020-02-19T03:00:47+01:00</published>
    <updated>2020-02-19T03:00:47+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:lang="en">
    <id>/blog/daft-punk/</id>
    <title>Daft Punk</title>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><strong>Daft Punk</strong> is a French <a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Electronic_music">electronic music</a> duo formed in Paris in 1993 by <a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Guy-Manuel_de_Homem-Christo">Guy-Manuel de Homem-Christo</a> and <a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thomas_Bangalter">Thomas Bangalter</a>. They achieved popularity in the late 1990s as part of the <a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/French_house">French house</a> movement; they also had success in the years following, combining elements of <a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/House_music">house music</a> with <a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Funk">funk</a>, <a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Techno">techno</a>, <a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Disco">disco</a>, rock and <a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Synthpop">synthpop</a>. They have worn ornate helmets and gloves to assume <a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robot">robot</a> personas in most public appearances since 1999 and rarely grant interviews or appear on television. The duo were managed from 1996 to 2008 by <a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pedro_Winter">Pedro Winter</a> (also known as Busy P), the head of <a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ed_Banger_Records">Ed Banger Records</a>.</p>
<!-- excerpt -->
<p>After Bangalter and Homem-Christo's <a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Indie_rock">indie rock</a> band <a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Darlin&#039;_(French_band)">Darlin'</a> disbanded, they began experimenting with <a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Drum_machine">drum machines</a> and synthesisers. Their debut studio album <em><a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Homework_(Daft_Punk_album)">Homework</a></em> was released by <a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Virgin_Records">Virgin Records</a> in 1997 to positive reviews, backed by singles &quot;<a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Around_the_World_(Daft_Punk_song)">Around the World</a>&quot; and &quot;<a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Da_Funk">Da Funk</a>&quot;. Their second album, <em><a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Discovery_(Daft_Punk_album)">Discovery</a>,</em> had further success, supported by hit singles &quot;<a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/One_More_Time_(Daft_Punk_song)">One More Time</a>&quot;, &quot;<a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digital_Love_(Daft_Punk_song)">Digital Love</a>&quot; and &quot;<a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Harder,_Better,_Faster,_Stronger">Harder, Better, Faster, Stronger</a>&quot;. In March 2005, Daft Punk released their third album, <em><a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Human_After_All">Human After All</a>,</em> to mixed reviews, though the singles &quot;<a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robot_Rock_(song)">Robot Rock</a>&quot; and &quot;<a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Technologic">Technologic</a>&quot; achieved success in the United Kingdom. Daft Punk <a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alive_2006/2007">toured throughout 2006 and 2007</a> and released the live album <em><a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alive_2007">Alive 2007</a></em>, which won a <a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Grammy_Award">Grammy Award</a> for <a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Grammy_Award_for_Best_Electronic/Dance_Album">Best Electronic/Dance Album</a>. They composed the score for the film <em><a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tron:_Legacy">Tron: Legacy</a></em>, which was released in 2010 alongside <a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tron:_Legacy_(soundtrack)">its soundtrack album</a>.</p>
<p>In 2013, Daft Punk left Virgin for <a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Columbia_Records">Columbia Records</a>, and released their fourth album, <em><a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Random_Access_Memories">Random Access Memories</a>,</em> to acclaim; lead single &quot;<a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Get_Lucky_(Daft_Punk_song)">Get Lucky</a>&quot; reached the top 10 in the charts of 32 countries. <em>Random Access Memories</em> won five Grammy Awards in 2014, including <a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Grammy_Award_for_Album_of_the_Year">Album of the Year</a> and <a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Grammy_Award_for_Record_of_the_Year">Record of the Year</a> for &quot;Get Lucky&quot;. In 2016, Daft Punk gained their first number one on the <a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Billboard_Hot_100"><em>Billboard</em> Hot 100</a> with the song &quot;<a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Starboy_(song)">Starboy</a>&quot;, a collaboration with <a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Weeknd">The Weeknd</a>. As of 2015, Daft Punk had sold over 12 million albums worldwide.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Source: <a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Daft_Punk">https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Daft_Punk</a></p>
</blockquote>]]>
    </content>
    <link href="/blog/daft-punk/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <published>2020-02-05T15:43:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2020-02-05T15:43:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
</feed>
