<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>/blog/</id>
  <title>English Blog - Blog</title>
  <subtitle><![CDATA[Blog of abstracts of scientific articles for CPE Lyon.]]></subtitle>
  <link href="/blog/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="/blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <updated>2020-03-18T14:00:24+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>English Blog</name>
    <uri>/</uri>
  </author>
  <entry xml:lang="en">
    <id>/blog/study-of-african-society-inspires-broad-thinking-about-human-paternity-fidelity/</id>
    <title>Study of African society inspires broad thinking about human paternity, fidelity</title>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>The article is about extra-pair paternity in an African society. The article is from <strong>phys.org</strong> and was written by <strong>Jessica Wolf</strong>.</p>
<p>A study from UCLA professor of anthropology Brooke Scelza made on an African society &quot;The Himba&quot; shows that the rate of extra-pair paternity found among Himba is 48% exceed the 1% to 10% range previously thought to be typical for humans. The &quot;extra-pair paternity&quot; refers to an instance in which a child is born to a married couple, but the husband is not the biological father.</p>
<p>The researcher contends that men not only are aware of this pattern, but they also have a system of social norms that support this practice. This research provides a new perspective in the study of human reproduction.</p>
<p><a href="https://phys.org/news/2020-02-african-society-broad-human-paternity.html">https://phys.org/news/2020-02-african-society-broad-human-paternity.html</a></p>]]>
    </content>
    <link href="/blog/study-of-african-society-inspires-broad-thinking-about-human-paternity-fidelity/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <published>2020-03-18T14:00:24+01:00</published>
    <updated>2020-03-18T14:00:24+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:lang="en">
    <id>/blog/coronavirus-telcos-are-taking-steps-to-meet-increased-demand-at-reduced-rates/</id>
    <title>Avoid the politics and let artificial intelligence decide your vote in the next election</title>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>The article deal with the solutions to optimize online learning with a five key. The article is from <strong>phys.org</strong> and was written by <strong>Frank Mols, Gary Mortimer And Jonathan Roberts.</strong> </p>
<p>AI is everywhere, music and video streaming services, online shoppings etc... As a result, why not use artificial intelligence to suggest whom we should vote for ?</p>
<p>The article identify two types of voters : the one who back the same party since a long time and the other, the &quot;swinging voters&quot; who compare options before making a choice. </p>
<p>Moreover, we can see thet politicians already use AI to target us.In the same way businesses use retargeting strategies to persuade us to buy or act, politicians now do the same.</p>
<p>If politicians are using AI to try to persuade us how to vote, why not flip this around and give us the AI tools needed to help us decide how to vote?</p>
<p>In our side, the voters, there are already a few tools to guide us, but nothing really advanced today</p>
<p><a href="https://phys.org/news/2019-05-politics-artificial-intelligence-vote-election.html">https://phys.org/news/2019-05-politics-artificial-intelligence-vote-election.html</a></p>]]>
    </content>
    <link href="/blog/coronavirus-telcos-are-taking-steps-to-meet-increased-demand-at-reduced-rates/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <published>2020-03-11T10:10:39+01:00</published>
    <updated>2020-03-11T10:10:39+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:lang="en">
    <id>/blog/how-to-optimize-online-learning-in-the-age-of-coronavirus/</id>
    <title>How to optimize online learning in the age of coronavirus</title>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>The article deal with the solutions to optimize online learning with a five key. The article is from <strong>phys.org</strong> and was written by <strong>Andrew Martin</strong>.</p>
<p>Due to the spread of the new coronavirus, online learning for school students is increasing. In order to remedy this, the educational psychologist who wrote this article, propose five key considerations for educators : Instruction, Content, Motivation, Relationships, Mental Health.</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Instruction</strong></li>
</ol>
<p>Regarding the principles of Load Reduction Instruction, online lessons must be very clear and well-structured, delivered in little chunks. When the the students have the basics, they can then provide more independent and self-directed online learning activities.</p>
<ol start="2">
<li><strong>Content</strong></li>
</ol>
<p>Moreover, the material is very important. The teacher have to be sure to use the best material in order to provide the most comfortable lesson to the students. Also, it is important that the content is not too difficult too soon in order to not confusing the student early in the learning process.</p>
<ol start="3">
<li><strong>Motivation</strong></li>
</ol>
<p>There is one area of motivation particularly relevant to online learning: self-regulation which is represented in the Wheel by self- and task-management, planning, and persistence.</p>
<ol start="4">
<li><strong>Relationships</strong></li>
</ol>
<p>Concerning this point, in an online environment, it is recommended that teachers maintain contact with the class in different ways, for instance : via email, the school's online learning platform, video, blogs, and class chat-groups.</p>
<ol start="5">
<li><strong>Mental Health</strong></li>
</ol>
<p>If mental health hurts, learning usually suffers. As a result, it is important that all students are clearly informed of who to contact inside or outside the school if they are in difficulties.</p>
<p><a href="https://phys.org/news/2020-03-optimize-online-age-coronavirus.html">https://phys.org/news/2020-03-optimize-online-age-coronavirus.html</a></p>]]>
    </content>
    <link href="/blog/how-to-optimize-online-learning-in-the-age-of-coronavirus/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <published>2020-03-04T17:33:40+01:00</published>
    <updated>2020-03-04T17:33:40+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:lang="en">
    <id>/blog/mathematicians-develop-new-theory-to-explain-real-world-randomness/</id>
    <title>Fast Share, Android's answer to Apple's AirDrop</title>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>The article deal with the possibility of sharing files between Android products easily. The article is from <strong>phys.org</strong> and was written by <strong>Peter Grad</strong>. </p>
<p>In brief, Google is preparing to launch a brand new app for file sharing between Android products in the update Android 11.</p>
<p>In fact, the application is not yet officially announced but some media analysts spotted a reference to a new Fast Share feature that will allow users to exchange files wirelessly if they are in close proximity. This reference was found in a bug report.</p>
<p>Regardless of the name, the feature will be a competitor of Apple's popular AirDrop, which lets users effortlessly transfer files between iOS and MacOS devices.</p>
<p><a href="https://techxplore.com/news/2020-03-fast-android-apple-airdrop-due.html">https://techxplore.com/news/2020-03-fast-android-apple-airdrop-due.html</a></p>]]>
    </content>
    <link href="/blog/mathematicians-develop-new-theory-to-explain-real-world-randomness/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <published>2020-02-26T16:36:53+01:00</published>
    <updated>2020-02-26T16:36:53+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:lang="en">
    <id>/blog/test/</id>
    <title>Seductive details inhibit learning</title>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>The article deal with the positive use of seductive details for learning. The article is from <strong>phys.org</strong> and was written by <strong>Sara Zaske</strong>.</p>
<p>All goes with a funny thing such as a cat video or even background music. Indeed, it can keep students from understanding the main content.</p>
<p>These so-called &quot;seductive details,&quot; information that is interesting but irrelevant, can be detrimental to learning by the look to a meta-analysis by Washington State University researchers published in the journal Educational Psychology Review recently.</p>
<p>This result was obtained by cross-referencing 58 studies and is as follows: People who learned with seductive details performed lower on learning outcome measures than those who learned without them.</p>
<p>Finally, that doesn't mean the course doesn't have to be cool, but just make a little more effort to think about how we can make the learning activity itself much more appealing and interesting, according to Sundar.,</p>
<p><a href="https://phys.org/news/2020-03-seductive-inhibit.html">https://phys.org/news/2020-03-seductive-inhibit.html</a></p>]]>
    </content>
    <link href="/blog/test/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <published>2020-02-19T03:00:47+01:00</published>
    <updated>2020-02-19T03:00:47+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
</feed>
